So a couple of years ago,
a woman I know who I'll call Maya,
went through a lot of big changes
in a short amount of time.
She got married.
She and her husband moved
for his job to a new city
where she didn’t know anyone.
She started a new role working from home,
all while managing her dad's
new diagnosis of dementia.
And to manage the stress
of all this change,
Maya doubled down on her physical
and mental health.
She exercised almost every day,
she ate healthy foods,
she went to therapy once a week.
And these actions really helped.
Her body got stronger.
Her mind got more resilient,
but only up to a point.
She was still struggling,
often losing sleep
in the middle of the night,
feeling unfocused,
unmotivated during the day.
Maya was doing everything
that doctors typically tell us to do
to be physically and mentally healthy,
and yet something was missing.
What if I told you
that what was missing for Maya
is also missing for billions
of people around the world,
and that it might be missing for you?
What if I told you that not having it
undermines our other efforts
to be healthy and can even
shorten your lifespan?
I’ve been studying this for over a decade,
and I've discovered
that the traditional way we think
about health is incomplete.
By thinking of our health
as primarily physical and mental,
we overlook what I believe
is the greatest challenge
and the greatest opportunity of our time.
Social health.
While physical health is about our bodies
and mental health is about our minds,
social health is about our relationships.
And if you haven't heard this term before,
that's because it hasn't yet
made its way into mainstream vocabulary,
yet it is equally important.
Maya didn't yet have a sense
of community in her new home.
She wasn't seeing her family,
or her friends or her coworkers
in person anymore,
and she often went weeks only spending
quality time with her husband.
Her story shows us
that we can't be fully healthy,
we can’t thrive, if we take
care of our bodies and our minds,
but not our relationships.
Similar to Maya,
hundreds of millions of people
around the world go weeks at a time
without talking to a single friend
or family member.
Globally, one in four people feel lonely.
And 20 percent of adults worldwide
don't feel like they have anyone
they can reach out to for support.
Think about that.
One in five people you encounter
may feel like they have no one.
This is more than heartbreaking.
It's also a public health crisis.
Disconnection triggers stress in the body.
It weakens people's immune systems.
It puts them at a risk, greater risk,
of stroke, heart disease, diabetes,
dementia, depression and early death.
Social health is essential for longevity.
So you might be wondering,
what does it look like
to be socially healthy?
What does that even mean?
Well it’s about developing
close relationships
with your family, your friends,
your partner, yourself.
It's about having regular interaction
with your coworkers, your neighbors.
It's about feeling like
you belong to a community.
Being socially healthy is about
having the right quantity
and quality of connection for you.
And Maya's story is one example
of how social health challenges come up.
In my work, I hear many others.
Stories like Jay,
a freshman in college
who’s eager to get involved in campus
yet is having a hard time
fitting in with people in his dorm
and often feels homesick.
Or Serena and Ali, a couple
juggling the chaos of young kids
with demanding jobs,
they rarely have time to see friends
or spend time one-on-one.
Or Henry, recently retired,
who cherishes time with his spouse
and yet feels untethered
without his team anymore
and wishes he could see his kids
and grandkids more often.
These stories show that social health
is relevant to each of us
at every life stage.
So if you're not sure where to start,
try the 5-3-1 guideline from my book.
It goes like this.
Aim to interact with five
different people each week,
to strengthen at least three
close relationships overall,
and to spend one hour a day connecting.
Let's dig into these.
So first, interact with five
different people each week.
Just like eating a variety of vegetables
and other food groups is more nutritious,
research has shown that interacting
with a variety of people
is more rewarding.
So your five could include close
loved ones, casual acquaintances,
even complete strangers.
In fact, in one study that I love,
people who just smiled, made eye contact
and chit-chatted with a barista,
felt happier and a greater
sense of belonging
than people who just rushed
to get their coffee and go.
Next, strengthen at least
three close relationships.
OK, we've all heard of a to-do list,
but I would like to invite you
to write a to-love list.
Who matters most to you?
Who can you be yourself with?
Make sure that you invest
in the names of at least three
of the people that you write down.
By scheduling regular time together,
by showing a genuine interest
in their lives,
and also by opening up
about the experiences
that you're going through.
And I'm often asked,
does it have to be in person?
Does texting count?
Studies have shown
that face-to-face is ideal,
so do that whenever possible.
But there are absolutely still benefits
to staying connected virtually.
And last, spend one hour a day
on meaningful connection.
OK, if you're an introvert,
right now you're probably thinking
one hour sounds like a lot.
I get it.
It might be surprising,
but I'm actually also an introvert.
However, keep in mind that just like
getting eight hours of sleep at night,
the exact amount
that's right for you personally
might be higher or lower.
But if you are thinking that one hour
a day sounds like way too much
because you're just way too busy,
I challenge you.
Adults in the US spend
an average of 4.5 hours
each day on their smartphones.
So instead of scrolling on social media,
text a friend.
Instead of reading news headlines,
write a thank-you card.
Instead of listening to a podcast,
call a family member.
Maya put this into practice
by scheduling recurring hangouts
with a new local friend that she made,
by attending community events
and dropping cards off
in her neighbors mailboxes,
by planning trips to see family
and inviting friends
in other cities to come visit.
And bolstering her social health
made more of a difference
than focusing solely on her physical
and mental health ever could.
And I know this because Maya
is actually me.
I am so passionate about sharing tools
to be socially healthy
because honestly, I need them too.
And the 5-3-1 guideline is one way
that we can be proactive
and intentional about our relationships.
And that is really the point.
Be proactive and intentional
about your social health.
So zooming out beyond the steps
that you and I take individually,
together, we need to shape a society
that thrives through social health.
Over the next decade,
I envision educators
championing social health in schools.
And just like kids build
their physical muscles in gym class,
they'll exercise their social muscles
in connection class.
Over the next decade,
I see our cities and neighborhoods
being designed with social health in mind,
where vibrant gathering
places foster unity
and community builders are empowered
to bring them to life.
Over the next decade,
I believe that social health
will become as ingrained
in our collective consciousness
as mental health is today.
Because not that long ago,
mental health was a taboo topic
shrouded in stigma.
And now public figures
talk openly about it,
there's an entire industry to support it,
and more and more people
think of going to therapy
like going to the gym.
In this future, loneliness will subside,
just like smoking subsided
when we recognized
and treated it as a public health issue.
In this future,
I hope that social health
will become so deeply woven
into the fabric of our culture
that no one needs
the 5-3-1 guideline anymore.
So to get there,
make relationships
your priority not only for you,
but also for the people you love.
Because the beauty of nurturing
your own social health
is that it naturally enriches
the social health
of everyone you connect with.
Thank you.
(Applause)